

# CONTACT



Email
MichaelDeanAh19@gmail.com



in Linkedin linkedin.com/in/michaelah19



# EDUCATION

High School Diploma Robert Thirsk High School 2013-2016

B.Sc. Geomatics Engineering University of Calgary, Canada 2016 - 2021

M.Eng. Software Engineering University of Calgary, Canada 2021-2022

# EXPERTISE

- Object Oriented Programming
- Software Dev (Python, C++)
- Front End (CSS3 & HTML5)
- Independent Learner
- MATLAB & Prototyping
- Revision Control (Perforce, GIT)
- Problem Solving & Debugging
- Agile/Scrum Development

# MICHAEL AH-KIOW

GEOMATICS ENGINEER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER DAY TRADER/TECHNICAL INVESTOR

#### PROFILE

I am a Geomatics and Software Engineer in training who is passionate about making this world a better place. I graduated with a Bachelor of Geomatics Engineering and I am currently in a Master of Software Engineering at the University of Calgary. I have industry experience in software development, research and working on agile teams. Feel free to visit my website at www.drivenengineer.ca

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Junior Software Developer Contractor**

SkyIT Services - Subsidiary of GBCS Group I 2020-Present (Part Time)

SkylT is a tech company that provides reliable, innovating, and exciting web app services to help the aviation industry overcome modern challenges.

- Research third party systems and technologies in Computer vision and IOT.
- Member of the development team that adhere to scrum principles with Kanban boards, bi-weekly sprints, and continuous improvement principles.

#### Research & Development Engineering Intern

Hexagon – Autonomy & Positioning I 2019-2020

At Hexagon I have worked on the development of exciting positioning technologies, from exploiting and protecting GNSS signals to:

- High Sensitivity GNSS algorithm testing, which include software development and debugging in C++, revision control using Perforce and working on an agile team with Jira.
- Development of an autonomous Car using Robotic Operating Systems (ROS),
   C++, Linux (Ubuntu), Python, Perforce and other Internal tools.
- Analysis, Visualization, and manipulation of massive GNSS & Inertial positioning datasets to better improve positioning algorithms.

### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

University of Calgary I 2018

My research consisted of applying 3D time of flight sensors to measure antler growth of reindeers at Spy Hill Campus for medical applications.

- Design and Implement a test setup using Time of Flight Cameras (Lidar technology) to monitor the growth and dimensions of Antler.
- Implemented various analysis and test scripts in C++, MATLAB and worked with industrial software development kits (SDK).

# CERTIFICATIONS

- Udemy: Modern HTML & CSSBy Brad Traversy (Udemy)
- SOLID Principles: Software Architecture & Design By Sujith George (Udemy)
- Machine Learning A to Z By Kirill Eremenko (Udemy)
- Python, SQL & Tableau
   By 365 Careers (Udemy)
- Advanced Python by Armendariz (Udemy)

### REFERENCES

#### Dr. Ivan Detchev

Engineering Professor PhD, MSc, Geomatics Engineering i.detchev@ucalgary.ca

# Darrell Anklovitch

Principal Engineer - Supervisor Hexagon Autonomy & Positioning Darrell.Anklovitch@hexagon.com

## Sean Blair

Volunteering Supervisor sean.blair@shaw.ca

# PHILANTHROPY

Children Believe

Tom Baker Cancer Center

World Food Programme

UNICEF

The Arthritis Society

The Crohn's & Colitis Society

Plan International Canada

# VOLUNTEERISM

St Peter Roman Catholic Church

**Drop-In Center** 

The Mustard Seed

Feed the Hungry

Robert Thirsk High School

Geomatics Engineering Student Society

#### EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

## **Vice President Academic**

Geomatics Engineering Student Society I 2018 - 2019

I served as a liaison between the faculty, the private sector, and the society. My job consisted of creating research positions, host career fair and research mixers.

#### **Engineering Student Team Member**

FUSE Collective Design Club I 2016 - 2017

FUSE collective is an engineering and design club that creates, designs, and participates in real initiatives with real-world impact. I was Involved in designing a shelter for Twin Views Community Garden

#### Math 30-1 Tutor

Robert Thirsk High School I 2015 - 2016

I offered peer tutoring and mentorship for students struggling in math class. I was also involved in grading, attendance and in organizing study sessions.

### **HONORS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

2016: President's Admission Scholarship. (Value: \$4,000)

Entrance scholarship to the engineering program for exceptional academic merit.

2016: Seymour Schulich Academic Excellence award. (Value: \$37,200) Full ride scholarship to the engineering program for academic excellence.

2016: Alexander Rutherford Scholarship. (Value: \$2500)

2017: Geomatics Engineering "25th Anniversary" Award. (Value: \$2,900)

2017, 2018: Jason Lang Scholarship. (Value: \$1000)

2018: Schulich Undergraduate Student Research Award. (Value: \$6000)

2019: Sean Studer Memorial Scholarship (Value: \$1500)

2020: Finalists/Bronze at the National Geomatics Competition (Value: \$300) Represented the University of Calgary a national engineering competition

2020: UCBeyond Scholarship 2020 (Value: \$5000):

Awarded for living above and beyond the boundaries of a chronic illness based on academic excellence, community involvement & personal ambition.

## **PROJECTS**

## Geolocation Mapping Tool

Python CLI project that plots Trajectory and errors of positioning logs.

Lidar reconstruction of reindeer's antler for Biomedical research Utilized a Time of flight camera and their C++ API to produce a 3D lidar image of antlers in real time.

Website Portfolio (https://www.drivenengineer.ca)

A fully responsive website written in CSS3 and HTML5.

#### Building Modelling by Mobile Phone Photogrammetry

Engineering Capstone supervised by Dr Lichti. (Currently in Progress)